Finding Aid for Chase S. Osborn Papers
Bentley Historical Library
Chase S. Osborn Papers
circa 1870-1949
1889-1949
Bentley Historical Library
Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), 1860-
86549 Aa 2; AC; UAl
149.9 linear feet ((in 152 boxes))
3 oversize volumes
1 oversize folder
Governor of Michigan, writer, businessman; papers include correspondence, business records, speeches, writings, visual materials, diaries.
The collection came to the library in many different accessions beginning in 1939. Prior to his death Governor Osborn donated miscellaneous publications and writings. Donor no. 238 Following his death in 1949, his widow, Stellanova Osborn donated the major corpus of Osborn papers. Donor no. 2668
The collection is open for research.
Chase Salmon Osborn was born January 22, 1860, in Huntington County, Indiana, to George A. and Margaret (Fannon) Osborn. Both of Osborn's parents were self-tutored medical doctors. Osborn attended Purdue University, 1874-1877, but left without graduating to become a newspaperman. Starting on the Lafayette (Indiana) Home Journal, Osborn worked successively on the Chicago Tribune and the Milwaukee Journal. In 1883 he moved north, purchasing the Florence (Wisconsin) Mining News. Over the next four years he also began prospecting for iron ore in the Menominee range. In 1887 he sold the newspaper and returned to Milwaukee as city editor of the Sentinel. At the same time, he helped establish and became editor of the Miner and Manufacturer (Milwaukee). Excited by the prospects of making his fortune in mining, Osborn left soon after for Sault Ste. Marie where he could be close to iron mining regions of Michigan and Ontario. To support himself he became part owner of the Sault Ste. Marie (Michigan) News which he published until 1901, approximately the same time as his discovery of a rich iron deposit in Ontario near Sudbury. With this discovery and other investments, Osborn had the money and the time to pursue other areas of interest. He did not immediately give up his newspaper career. In 1902 he bought a half interest in the Saginaw (Michigan) Courier-Herald which he held until 1912.
Long before Osborn left the newspaper business, he expressed an interest in Michigan politics as a Republican. From 1889 to 1893 he served as postmaster of Sault Ste. Marie; he was state fish and game warden, 1895 to 1899; state commissioner of railroads, 1899-1903; regent for The University of Michigan, 1908-1911; and governor, 1911 to 1912. He was unsuccessful congressional candidate in 1896, an unsuccessful aspirant for nomination as the Republican candidate for United States senator in 1918, Michigan's favorite son candidate for the Republican vice-presidential nomination in 1928, and an unsuccessful candidate for the Republican nomination for the United States Senate in 1930. Consistently progressive in his political sentiments, Osborn refused to bolt the Republican party in 1912, although he finally did vote for Roosevelt.
From 1887 on Osborn made his home in Sault Ste. Marie and on nearby Duck Island. In later years he wintered in Possum Poke, Worth County, Georgia. After 1912, Osborn devoted himself to lecturing, travel, writing, and to his investments. He authored thirteen books relating to American history, politics, Indian lore, and travel. Osborn died in Georgia on April 11, 1949.
The Osborn collection has been arranged into twelve series: Correspondence; Personal Letterbooks; State Game and Fish Warden; Biographical and Genealogical Materials; Diaries; Speeches; Political Papers; Mining, Timber, and Land Investments; Topical Files, Writings, Scrapbooks, and Photographs.
The Osborn collection consists of correspondence, diaries, business papers, scrapbooks, photographs, and other materials accumulated during his life. Materials prior to 1889 are scarce possibly because of a fire which destroyed Osborn's home; thereafter and up to the time of his death in 1949, the Osborn papers are voluminous, documenting each of this man's varied activities. Although his career as elected public official was limited to one term as governor, the collection reflects the importance of his life in areas beyond politics alone. His voice was heard, in letters and speeches and monographs, speaking out on the issues of the day - prohibition, conservation, the New Deal, and of course his life-long interest in the development of Michigan's Upper Peninsula economy and natural resources.
American newspapers -- Michigan -- Sault Sainte Marie.; Authors, American -- Michigan.; Conservation of natural resources -- Michigan.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1896.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1898.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1900.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1908.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1910.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1912.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1914.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1928.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1932.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1936.; Elections -- Michigan -- 1940.; Governors -- Michigan.; Governors -- Michigan.; Madagascar.; Michigan -- Politics and government -- 1877-1898.; Michigan -- Politics and government -- 1899-1916.; Michigan -- Politics and government -- 1917-1921.; Michigan -- Politics and government -- 1922-1928.; Michigan -- Politics and government -- 1929-1938.; Michigan -- Politics and government -- 1939-1945.; Michigan -- Politics and government -- 1946-1960.; Mines and mineral resources -- United States.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1896.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1900.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1908.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1912.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1928.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1932.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1936.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1940.; Saginaw courier herald.; Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.); Sit-down strikes -- Michigan.; Temperance -- Michigan.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1865-1933.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1933-1945.; Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Afro-Americans -- Georgia -- Work.; Bridges.; Burma.; Camping.; Cement industries.; Death.; Duck Island (Chippewa County, Mich.); Dwellings.; Funeral rites and ceremonies.; Governors -- Michigan.; Governors -- Michigan.; Hunting -- United States.; Interiors.; Isle Royale (Mich.); Log cabins.; Lumber industry.; Newberry (Mich.); Offices.; Pictured Rocks (Mich.); Political elections -- 1911-1912.; Political parades and rallies.; Ramsay (Mich.); Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.); Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.) -- Dwellings.; Tahquamenon River (Mich.); United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; Veterans -- Michigan.; Cartoons.; Daguerreotypes.; Diaries.; Photographs.; Prints.; Scrapbooks.; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), 1860-; Progressive Party (1912); Republican Party (Mich.); Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; United States. Congress -- Elections, 1932.; University of Michigan. Board of Regents.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), 1860-; Osborn, Stellanova, 1894-1988.; Osborn family.; Petoskey Portland Cement Company.; Republican Party (Mich.). State Convention (1912: Bay City, Mich.); Rockland High School (Rockland, Mich.); Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 8th (1861-1865); University of Michigan. Board of Regents.; Adams, Henry Carter, 1851-1921.; Alger, R. A. (Russell Alexander), 1836-1907.; Andrews, Roger, 1874-; Angell, Carleton Watson, 1887-1963.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Beal, Junius E. (Junius Emery), 1860-1942.; Beveridge, Albert Jeremiah, 1862-1927.; Bliss, Aaron Thomas, 1837-1906.; Booth, Edmund Wood, 1866-1927.; Brewster, Ralph O.; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Burrows, Julius C. (Julius Caesar), 1837-1915.; Chapin, Roy D. (Roy Dikeman), 1880-1936.; Codd, George Pierre, 1869-1927.; Comstock, William Alfred, 1877-1949.; Cooley, Mortimer E. (Mortimer Elwyn), 1855-1944.; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.; Cotter, William Edward, 1893-1957.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Curtis, Charles.; Dame, Gilman Marston, 1866-1939.; Davidson, O. C.; DeFoe, Murl Holcomb, 1879-; De Kruif, Paul, 1890-1971.; Denby, Edwin, 1870-1929.; Dewey, Edmund Otis, 1861-1921.; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Dickinson, Luren Dudley, 1859-1943.; Dix, Dorothea Lynde, 1802-1887.; Doyle, Edward H., 1849-1919.; Ferris, Woodbridge N., 1853-1928.; Fletcher, Frank Ward, 1853-1922.; Ford, Henry, 1863-1947.; Fordney, Joseph W. (Joseph Warren), 1853-1932.; Green, Fred W. (Fred Warren), 1872-1936.; Groesbeck, Alexander J. (Alexander Joseph), 1873-1953.; Guest, Edgar A. (Edgar Albert), 1881-1959.; Hanchett, Benjamin Sawtell, 1868-1933.; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923.; Hoard, W. D. (William Dempster), 1836-1918.; Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Horton, George B.; Hough, Emerson, 1857-1923.; Hubbard, Lucius L. (Lucius Lee), 1849-1933.; Humphrey, Watts S.; Hunsaker, Walter Jerome, 1857-1939.; Hutchins, Harry B. (Harry Burns), 1847-1930.; Kelley, Patrick Henry, 1867-1925.; Kellogg, John Harvey, 1852-1943.; Kemp, Edward Gearing, 1887-1962.; Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.; La Follette, Robert M. (Robert Marion), 1855-1925.; Landon, Alfred M. (Alfred Mossman), 1887-1987.; Lorch, Emil, 1870-1963.; Loveman, Amy.; McKinley, William, 1843-1901.; McMillan, James, 1838-1902.; MacNoughton, James.; Mapes, Carl Edgar, 1874-1939.; Mather, William Gwinn, 1857-1951.; May, Thomas, 1860-1927.; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956.; Mershon, William Briggs.; Montgomery, Robert M., 1849-1920.; Morley, George Bidwell, 1857-1935.; Murfin, James Orin, 1875-1940.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Musselman, Amos S., 1851-; Newberry, Truman Handy, 1864-1945.; Palmer, Calvin A.; Pegler, Westbrook, 1894-1969.; Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943.; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946.; Pingree, Hazen S., 1840-1901.; Powers, Perry Francis, 1857-1945.; Pyle, Ernie, 1900-1945.; Rich, John Treadway, 1841-1926.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Roosevelt, Kermit, 1889-1943.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Russell, Richard B. (Richard Brevard), 1897-1971.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Sawyer, Walter H. (Walter Hulme), 1861-1931.; Schermerhorn, James, 1865-1942.; Scott, Fred Newton, 1860-1931.; Shafer, John C.; Shields, Robert Hazen, 1905-; Sigler, Kim, 1894-; Sink, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1879-1972.; Sleeper, Albert E., 1862-1934.; Sligh, Charles Robert, 1850-1927.; Smith, Shirley Wheeler, 1875-1959.; Smith, William Alden, 1859-1932.; Sparks, Frank Melville, 1877-1950.; Stair, W. D.; Stone, Ralph, 1868-1956.; Sullivan, Mark, 1874-1952.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; Talmadge, Herman E. (Herman Eugene), 1913-2002.; Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924.; Underwood, Frederick Douglas, -1942.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Van Hise, Charles Richard, 1857-1918.; Warner, Frederick Maltby, 1865-1923.; White, William A. (William Alanson), 1870-1937.; Willard, Daniel, 1861-1942.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927.; Zimmerman, Fred R.
- Correspondence, 1889-1949
  The Correspondence series (1889-1949; 99.5 linear feet) is by far the largest series in the Osborn papers. As a public figure, Osborn corresponded widely and frequently with other notables, business associates, and a legion of acquaintances and admirers who had known him as newspaper publisher, governor, businessman, mining and land speculator, and author. The total of Osborn letters in the collection probably numbers close to 200, 000 items. Osborn corresponded with nearly every major Republican political leader in Michigan, as well as with many minor politicos within the party, prominent Democratic Party leaders, and other newspapermen. Osborn's business and political interests and his research projects are obviously principal topics within the letters. Included are correspondence from every president from McKinley to Truman. Of special note is correspondence with many prominent Progressives including Theodore Roosevelt concerning the campaign of 1912, and material on the elections of 1904, 1908, 1910, 1912, 1916, 1918, 1920, and 1930. Osborn's own campaigns for governor in 1910 and his candidacy for the U.S. Senate in 1930 are also well documented.
  The chronological arrangement that Osborn maintained for his files, especially in a collection of this size poses some difficulties for the researcher. As his correspondence is not arranged by topic, the researcher must display some diligence in uncovering the great wealth of information that Osborn's communications contain. Essential is a sense of the chronology of Osborn's life. With that, the researcher will be rewarded with correspondence with significant individuals discussing the issues of the day: progressivism, conservation, Upper Peninsula development, state government, and national politics. There is, for example, correspondence showing progressive concern over business-government relations (cf. correspondence with Frederick D. Underwood, president of the B & O, and the Pennsylvania). The correspondence also includes much discussion of foreign relations: British colonial policies, the Boer War, British-German, British-United States, Canadian-United States relations, the Russo-Japanese War, China, and Chile and the Philippines. Other topics include contemporary political, social and intellectual issues: imperialism, nationalism, Anglo-Saxon racism, regulation of utilities and railroads, monetary and international trade policies, conservation, radicalism and socialism, German immigration, Anti-Semitism, Anti-Mormonism, Anti-Catholicism, prison reform, urban redevelopment and beautification, prohibition, and woman's suffrage. To aid the researcher, the library has prepared a separate index to the correspondents and a selective index to topics. This card inventory is located in the Reading Room of the library. Topics indexed in this file include Anglo-Saxon racism (1898-1899), progressivism and anti-progressivism (1908-1919), prohibition (1914-1926), forest conservation (1907-1926), labor and labor unions (1910-1921), and woman suffrage (1901-1917).
  The Correspondence for the period of 1889 to 1908 is arranged alphabetically within a specific period of time, usually a few months. Apparently, Osborn maintained his correspondence in letterboxes. When one filled up, he started another. The correspondence for 1909 to 1949 is arranged only by chronology. These files might have been arranged alphabetically like the earlier files and then rearranged at a later date into a solely chronological sequence.
  The Correspondence series also includes card index to correspondence (1 small box).
  - Card index to correspondence (Box 150)
  - A-Z, 1889-1892 (Box 1)
  - A-Z, 1893-March 1895 (Box 1)
  - A-Z, 1894 (Box 1)
  - A-C, 1895 (Box 1)
  - D-Z, 1895 (Box 2)
  - A-Z, April 1895-January 1896 (Box 2)
  - A-Z, January-April 1896 (Box 2)
  - A-C, May-July 1896 (Box 2)
  - D-Z, May-July 1896 (Box 3)
  - A-Z, August-December 1896 (Box 3)
  - A-L, January-May 1897 (Box 3)
  - M-Z, January-May 1897 (Box 4)
  - A-Z, June-December 1897 (Box 4)
  - A-Q, January-July 1898 (Box 4)
  - R-Z, January-July 1898 (Box 5)
  - A-Z, July-September 1898 (Box 5)
  - A-Z, October 1898-January 1899 (Box 5)
  - A-Z, February-March 1899 (Box 6)
  - A-Z, April-May 1899 (Box 6)
  - A-J, June-August 1899 (Box 6)
  - K-Z, June-August 1899 (Box 7)
  - A-Z, September-December 1899 (Box 7)
  - A-L, January-February 1900 (Box 7)
  - M-Z, January-February 1900 (Box 8)
  - A-Z, February-April 1900 (Box 8)
  - A-S, April-June 1900 (Box 8)
  - T-Z, April-June 1900 (Box 9)
  - A-Z, July-October 1900 (Box 9)
  - A-Z, November 1900-January 1901 (Box 9)
  - A-C, February-May 1901 (Box 9)
  - D-Z, February-May 1901 (Box 10)
  - A-Z, May-November 1901 (Box 10)
  - A-E, December 1901-February 1902 (Box 10)
  - F-Z, December 1901-February 1902 (Box 11)
  - A-Z, March-June 1902 (Box 11)
  - A-M, July-November 1902 (Box 11)
  - N-Z, July-November 1902 (Box 12)
  - A-Z, December 1902-June 1903 (Box 12)
  - A-R, June-December 1903 (Box 12)
  - A-Z, January-August 1904 (Box 13)
  - A-J, 1905 (Box 13)
  - K-Z, 1905 (Box 14)
  - A-Z, January-June 1906 (Box 14)
  - A-C, July-December 1906 (Box 14)
  - D-Z, July-December 1906 (Box 15)
  - A-Z, January-August 1907 (Box 15)
  - A-Z, October 1907-January 1908 (Box 16)
  - A-Z, February-April 1908 (Box 16)
  - A-Z, May-June 1908 (Box 16)
  - N-Z, May-June 1908 (Box 17)
  - Caribou experiment file (Box 17)
  - A-Z, July-October 1908 (Box 17)
  - A-Z, November-December 1908 (Box 17)
  - January-September 1909 (Box 18)
  - October-December 1909 (Box 19)
  - January-February 1910 (Box 20)
  - March 1-May 11, 1910 (Box 21)
  - May 12-August 31, 1910 (Box 22)
  - September-November 15, 1910 (Box 23)
  - November 16-December 31, 1910 (Box 24)
  - January-March 1911 (Box 25)
  - April-July 1911 (Box 26)
  - August-December 23, 1911 (Box 27)
  - December 24, 1911-February 1912 (Box 28)
  - March 1-June 8, 1912 (Box 29)
  - June 9-September 22, 1912 (Box 30)
  - September 23-December 31, 1912 (Box 31)
  - January 1, 1913-July 6, 1914 (Box 32)
  - July 7-August 8, 1914 (Box 33)
  - August 9-September 15, 1914 (Box 34)
  - September 16-December 8, 1914 (Box 35)
  - December 9, 1914-July 31, 1915 (Box 36)
  - August 1, 1915-January 31, 1916 (Box 37)
  - 1916-1937, undated (Box 37)
  - February-May 1916 (Box 38)
  - June-December 1916 (Box 39)
  - January 1-December 20, 1917 (Box 40)
  - December 21, 1917-May 31, 1918 (Box 41)
  - June-August 1918 (Box 42)
  - September 1, 1918-June 10, 1919 (Box 43)
  - July 11-November 30, 1919 (Box 44)
  - December 1919-March 1920 (Box 45)
  - April-October 1920 (Box 46)
  - November 1, 1920-May 10, 1921 (Box 47)
  - May 11-September 30, 1921 (Box 48)
  - October 1, 1921-March 15, 1922 (Box 49)
  - March 16-December 31, 1922 (Box 50)
  - 1923 (Box 51)
  - 1924 (Box 52)
  - January-October 1925 (Box 53)
  - November 1925-June 1926 (Box 54)
  - July 1926-February 1927 (Box 55)
  - March 1-November 10, 1927 (Box 56)
  - November 11, 1927-May 10, 1928 (Box 57)
  - May 11, 1928-December 31, 1928 (Box 58)
  - January 1929-December 1929 (Box 146)
  - January-June 1930 (Box 59)
  - July-December 1930 (Box 147)
  - January-December 1931 (Box 148)
  - January-December 1932 (Box 149)
  - January-August 20, 1933 (Box 60)
  - August 21, 1933-April 1934 (Box 61)
  - May-November 1934 (Box 62)
  - December 1934-April 10, 1935 (Box 63)
  - April 11, 1935-October 31, 1935 (Box 64)
  - November 1, 1935-February 20, 1936 (Box 65)
  - February 21, 1936-August 10, 1936 (Box 66)
  - August 11, 1936-December 31, 1936 (Box 67)
  - January 1-May 5, 1937 (Box 68)
  - May 6-October 31, 1937 (Box 69)
  - November 1, 1937-January 22, 1938 (Box 70)
  - January-December 1938, 2 folders (Box 70)
    (later accession)
  - January 23, 1938-May 20, 1938 (Box 71)
  - May 21-October 31, 1938 (Box 72)
  - November 1938-February 5, 1939 (Box 73)
  - 1939-1940 (Box 73)
  - February 6-May 10, 1939 (Box 74)
  - May 11-September 27, 1939 (Box 75)
  - September 28-December 17, 1939 (Box 76)
  - December 18, 1939-February 8, 1940 (Box 77)
  - February 9-March 31, 1940 (Box 78)
  - April-May 1940 (Box 79)
  - June-November 1940 (Box 80)
  - 1941-1944 (Box 80)
  - December 1940-February 10, 1941 (Box 81)
  - February 11-May 24, 1941 (Box 82)
  - May 25-November 1941 (Box 83)
  - December 1941-April 15, 1942 (Box 84)
  - April 16, 1942-October, 1942 (Box 85)
  - November 1942-February, 1943 (Box 86)
  - March-July, 1943 (Box 87)
  - August-December, 1943 (Box 88)
  - January-April 25, 1944 (Box 89)
  - April 26, 1944-January 5, 1945 (Box 90)
  - January 6-June 30, 1945 (Box 91)
  - July-December, 1945 (Box 92)
  - November 1944-December 1945, 4 folders (Box 92)
  - January-June 1946 (Box 93)
  - July-December 1946 (Box 94)
  - 1946-1947 (Box 94)
  - January-May 1947 (Box 95)
  - June-December 1947 (Box 96)
  - January-June 1948 (Box 97)
  - January-December 1948, 3 folders (Box 97)
  - July 1948-March 1949 (Box 98)
  - March-April 1949 (Box 98)
  - 1949, 1 folder (Box 98)
  - And Miscellaneous Correspondence, Undated; 9 folders (Box 99)
  - Correspondence with family, 1920-1926; 8 folders (Box 99)
- Personal Letterbooks, 1895-1912
  In addition to files of correspondence, the collection includes a series of Personal Letterbooks dated 1895 to 1912 (8 linear feet).
  - June 21, 1895-January 17, 1898 (Box 100)
  - January 17, 1898-December 20, 1899 (Box 101)
  - December 20, 1899-January 17, 1902 (Box 102)
  - January 13, 1902-January 6, 1905 (Box 103)
  - January 6, 1905-July 7, 1908 (Box 104)
  - July 6, 1908-June 21, 1910 (Box 105)
  - June 21, 1910-March 22, 1912 (Box 106)
  - March 22, 1912-December 31, 1912 (Box 107)
- State Game and Fish Warden, 1895-1899
  The State Game and Fish Warden series (2.5 linear feet; 1895-1899) includes letterbooks of outgoing Osborn correspondence, 1895-1899, as well as the reports written by Osborn in that period.
  - Letterbooks, February 5, 1895-July 27, 1896 (Box 107)
  - Letterbooks, August 1, 1896-August 25, 1898 (Box 108)
  - Letterbooks, August 26, 1898-April 4, 1899 (Box 109)
  - Reports, 1895-1899; 1 folder, 1 folder (Box 109)
- Biographical and Genealogical Materials
  Biographical and Genealogical Materials (1 linear foot) consists of biographical sketches of Osborn and collected material about different family lines.
  - Biographical Sketches of CSO, 3 folders (Box 110)
  - Articles and pamphlets about CSO, 2 folders (Box 110)
  - Biographical material, 2 folders (Box 110)
  - Data on the subject of CSO (Box 110)
  - "About Chase Osborn", Vols. I-IV
    - Vol. I (Box 110)
    - Vol. II (Box 110)
    - Vol. III-IV (Box 110)
  - Quotes and Anecdotes used by CSO (Box 110)
  - Genealogical papers
    - Correspondence and miscellanea (Box 110)
    - Osborn Family, 5 folders (Box 110)
    - Fannon Family (Box 110)
    - Jeffries Family (Box 110)
    - Pardee Family (Box 110)
- Diaries
  Osborn Diaries are dated 1890, 1895-1915 and 1935 and concern daily events and activities.
  - 1890, 1895-1915; 1935 (Box 111)
- Speeches, undated; 1895-1930
  Speeches are arranged chronologically and concern political, literary, and historical topics.
  - Undated, 1895-1912; 14 folders (Box 111)
  - 1913-1940, 8 folders (Box 112)
  - Speaking Engagements
    - 1928 (Box 112)
    - 1929 (Box 112)
    - 1930, 2 folders (Box 112)
  - Speech programs (Box 112)
- Political Papers, 1900-1940
  Political papers (1900-1940; 2 linear feet) concern Osborn's 1910 gubernatorial campaign, miscellaneous papers from his term as governor, and his bid for nomination to the United States Senate in 1930.
  - Delegates to State Nominating Convention, 1900 (Box 112)
  - Gubernatorial campaign, 1910
    - 1910 Campaign Materials, 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Political cartoons from newspapers (Box 112)
    - Osborn supporters (Box 112)
      (arranged alphabetically by county)
  - Gubernatorial miscellanea
    - First inaugural message, 1911 (Box 112)
    - Appointment book, 1912 (Box 112)
    - Railroad and corporation taxation reports to Osborn as governor (Box 112)
    - Appointment powers as governor, decisions (Box 112)
    - Appointments to boards and commissions (Box 112)
    - Proclamations as governor, circa 1911 (Box 112)
    - Hearings before Governor Chase S. Osborn on the removal of Robert H. Shields from the Board of State Tax Commissioners, June 1912 (Box 112)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 112)
  - Political County book, 1914 (Box 113)
  - Senatorial campaign, 1918
    - Lists, etc., 1918 (Box 113)
  - Senatorial campaign, 1930
    - Miscellaneous (Box 113)
    - Campaign office correspondence files (George Osborn, Fed Case, et al), 12 folders (Box 113)
      (arranged alphabetically)
    - Master lists of county campaigners (Box 113)